Umair Liagat

Junior Flutter Developer

I am Junior Flutter mobile applications developer with proven experience in creating and building Flutter applications, for android and IOS platforms. Strong expertise in building applications with Firebase as a database. Have grip in working on APIs. I posses good problem solving skills



umairliagat552@gmail.com

0313-4146-206

Lahore, Pakistan

linkedin.com/in/umair-liaqat-305450228

github.com/Umairliagat33

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Flutter Developer **CYBRNODE**

11/2022 - 03/2023

Lahore

That was software house specialized in building web and mobile apps Project Ownership

- I was working solely on a project named as Switch Driver at CYBRNODE.
- Problems with logic: Using my problem solving skill, i created many difficult logics there.
- Track a user's location and showing it on map. I solved it swiftly by adding a small piece of code.

Contact: Umar - umar@cybrnode.com

Customer Support Representative Team Lead Digital Estimating

08/2021 - Present

This is a construction estimation firm where we help US contractors with bidding process which is before construction.

Team Lead

- Within a short interval of time i had achieved the position of a team lead for CSR department there.
- On call recording: Before i was working there, there was no way to track a call from a client after we answer it. I solved that issue, using a screen recorder and keeping those recordings save.
- Problem to train new hires: When a new employee for the position of CSR was hired there was no way to train him then giving him real life experience which can cause losing of customers, I solved it by storing some important call recordings which will help new hire to understand the nature of calls he will be receiving.

Contact: HR - 042 38934325

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Software Engineering - BSSE University of South Asia - Cantt campus

10/2020 - Present Lahore

Courses

 Object Oriented Programming

Advance Programming

- Software Requirement **Specifications**

 Software Project management

SKILLS

Problem solving Flutter Development Quick learning Python Coding Standards UI/UX design Computer Science Provider

ACHIEVEMENTS

Flutter internship (07/2022 - 10/2022)

I completed my internship in flutter from CYBRNODE. There i got to learn a lot of new things that i had never hear of before. Most important thing I got to learn was code writing style and code *formattina*

FESTIVASIA 4th edition winner (03/2023 - 03/2023)

A inter-university app development competition was held in our university with the help of Softech society. 4-5 teams were competing in that competition and we were given a small application to build. We won that competition with first position.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Mera Godamm (11/2023 - 12/2023)

This is an inventory management application specially developed for Shoes wholesalers, it helps them to keep a record of their inventory and also helps them keep a record of their daily sales instead of keep it on paper.

My Expense (09/2021 - 11/2021)

- My expense is a book keeping software which helps anyone to keep record of their expenses digitally, instead of going through the hassle of writing everything on paper.

Flashlight (02/2022 - 02/2022)

This was a simple flashlight application that i built using for practice purpose, which can turn your smartphone's flashlight ON/OFF.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Flutter/Dart Professional Working Proficiency

Elementary Proficiency